Daniel Borislavov Simeonov

Desired Position: Junior Front End Developer

Phone: +447518 866212 | Email: dbsimeonov@yahoo.com
Address: 84 Geary Road, Willesden, London NW101HR
DOB: 11.08.1996 | Nationality: Bulgarian (EU/EEA)
GitHub Portfolio: github.com/dbsimeonov/

Personal Profile

An enthusiastic, confident and ambitious individual with passion for technologies, mixture of SASS and JavaScript experience and excellent communication and organisational skills at all levels. Good team player, able to manage high volume of workload in a calm and constructive manner and enjoy working to a high standard whilst still understanding the need to work to tight deadlines and established schedule. Highly motivated with good knowledge of structured programming language and keen to learn and develop new skills. Proactive communicator with good eye for details, ability to work within busy environments, deal with members of the public and ensure work is delivered on time and to required specifications.

Career Objective

Seeking a full time, permanent Junior Front End Developer position within growth orientated company that will benefit from my outstanding employment record, excellent social skills and good technology and software knowledge. I'm ready for my first step up into a fully integrated digital and development environment and am determined to drive continuous improvement.

Key Skills

- Effective oral, written, communication and interpersonal skills;
- · Strong management and leadership skills;
- Tidy appearance, very good typing skills and telephone manner;
- Initiative and ability to work under pressure;
- Ability to establish positive and professional relationships with colleagues, clients and management team;
- Strong analytical and complex problem solving skills;
- Able to work with wide range of customers and communicate technical issues regardless of their background or profession;
- Practical abilities good with new technologies, tools and equipment;
- Technical knowledge; expert understanding of new technologies, through knowledge of Windows, Linux and MS Office; excellent understanding of information systems, software configuration, LAN and troubleshoot configuration, reading and analysing application logs, hardware or software problems etc.
- Software & IT knowledge Opera, OnQ, Macros, Google Sheets, Adobe Photoshop, Mac Terminal, Research, Quick-learner, Social Media;
- Experienced with bench power supplies, oscilloscopes, very good soldering skills;
- Experience in website development, upgrading, configuring and debugging existing systems;
- Excellent attention to details;
- Outstanding customer service skills;
- Hard working person with a can do attitude;

Experience with the following: ● HTML ● CSS ● JavaScript ● Sass ● Bootstrap ● Materialize ● Git **Languages:** ● Bulgarian Language (Native) ● English Language

Education and Qualifications

- Level 4 HNC in Business Management Kensington College of Business, Oxford Circus, London 2017
- Diploma of General Secondary Education Electronic and Mechanical Vocational School, Lovech, Bulgaria 2012 – 2015
 - Professional Qualification: Computer Engineer
 - Completed mandatory work experience in computer software & engineering

CPD:

- **uDemy website** two years continuous personal development in computer software & technologies.
- FreeCodeCamp & CodeBar non-profit platform organisations that consist of an interactive learning web platform, an online community forum, chat rooms, Medium publications and local organisations that intend to make learning web development accessible to anyone. Throughout the last one year I have been learning, sharing my experience with other members and earning constructive and valuable feedback on my coding and programming language skills.

Employment History

Front of House Receptionist/Administrator – Borehamwood Travelodge, London (2017 - Current)

General responsibilities:

- Demonstrating visionary leadership, coordinating activities, directing and controlling the operation of the hotel front office;
- Meeting and greeting hotel guests; checking guests in and out, issuing room keys;
- Performing various administrative jobs updating records, filling forms, producing documents, sending emails and letters, managing archive system;
- Handling high volume of telephone calls, resolving problems and disputes;
- Full management of hotel bookings and utilising online booking software to maximise covers during busy times;
- Liaising with hotel guests either over the phone or face to face, resolving issues, managing cancellations and processing payment refunds where necessary;
- Proactively dealing with any IT and server elated issues as they arise;
- Working closely with office and management team, assisting in managing the company website, web optimisation, maintaining web apps and improving internal IT systems;
- Inspecting quality of cleanliness in guest rooms prior to evening occupancy;
- Responding to guests queries in a timely and efficient manner, acting in accordance with hotel policies and procedures;
- Processing cash and card payments and giving out change and receipts; preparing cash drawers and managing petty cash;
- Liaising with other departments (Housekeeping, Restaurant, Maintenance) and ensuring guests receive a memorable hotel stay;
- Assisting during busy periods and developing specialised skills across all departments;
- Demonstrating exceptional customer service, receiving positive and constructive feedback from hotel guests and Management team;
- Participating in meetings, presenting financial and statistics information to Management team;
- Carrying out inspections of property and services:
- Monitoring stock and ordering supplies;

Front of House Night Receptionist/Administrator – Hilton Green Park, London (September 2015 – May 2017)

My commitment to work can be assessed from the fact that in October 2015 I joined Hilton Green Park as an Assistant Chef and shortly after I was promoted to Front of House Night Receptionist & Administrator. Personal accomplishments include:

- Employee of the Month Award 2016
- Outstanding Performance Award 2016

General responsibilities:

- Working night shifts, coordinating activities, directing and controlling the operation of the hotel front office;
- Meeting and greeting evening hotel guests; checking guests in and out, issuing room keys;
- Processing cash and card payments and giving out change and receipts; preparing cash drawers and managing petty cash;
- Performing various administrative jobs updating records, filling forms, producing documents, sending emails and letters, managing archive system;
- Responsible for managing the financial control, reporting and management information;
- Performing financial day-end closing, reviewing statistics and documentation and ensuring that all financial and business transactions from the current day have been correctly processed;
- Carrying out daily financial audits, reviewing all payment transactions and ensuring revenue recognition is accurate and received timely;
- Proactively dealing with any IT and server elated issues as they arise;
- Working closely with office and management team, assisting in managing the company website, web optimisation, maintaining web apps and improving internal IT systems;
- Liaising with other departments (Housekeeping, Restaurant, Maintenance) and ensuring guests receive a memorable hotel stay;
- Carrying out other duties and responsibilities, including night room service, security and concierge services;
- Demonstrating exceptional customer service, receiving positive and constructive feedback from hotel guests and Management team;
- Participating in meetings, presenting financial and statistics information to Management team;
- · Carrying out inspections of property and services;

Maintenance Technician – ILIT Nightclub, Lovech, Bulgaria (2014 - 2015)

Providing a professional and innovative services within the Maintenance team, responsible for maintaining and fixing all sound hardware and software systems within the nightclub to ensure clarity and precise coverage over the whole dance floor. Set up and connection of all new and existing electronic equipment, diagnosing and fixing faults, repairing and replacing faults, connecting cables and circuits and ensuring compliance with H&S and Government regulations.

PCB Repair Apprentice – Work Experience (2013 - 2014)

Repairing obsolete and damaged TV equipment – identifying and diagnosing faults, responsible for repair and calibration of PCB's, demonstrating outstanding soldering skills.

References

References are available upon request.